<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata version="1.0">
  <uniqueid id="in.nlci.fonts.Vaigai.0.703" />
  <vendor name="NLCI" url="http://www.nlci.in/fonts/" />
  <credits>
    <credit
      name="Dev NLCI"
      url="http://www.nlci.in/fonts/"
      role="NLCI designers and font engineers"
    />
  </credits>
  <description>
    <text lang="en">
      Pan Tamil font designed to support all the languages using the Tamil script.
      
      Known issues
      ------------
      U+0B94 and U+0BB6 might need N APs
      Old style glyphs need to be enabled in a ss
      Reph stype RA needs to be enabled, maybe in a cv
      U+0BB6 need major changes.
      U+0BD0 needs to be slightly visually changed.
      U+0BF3 needs to have right sten removed.
      U+0BF7 needs a curl at the top.
      U+0BFA needs a curl at the top.
      u0B95_u0BC2.old in Auvaiyar needs to be redrawn to match the overall style.
      U+20B9 needs to be made italic in the Italic and Bold Italic faces
      The ring in u1CF5 needs to be removed
      u0B99_u0BCD.alt in Auvaiyar needs to be copied from u0B99_u0BCD and then copy the ring-shaped pulli from u0B82
      
      ChangeLog
      ---------
      (This should list both major and minor changes, most recent first.)
      
      31 May 2021 (Dev NLCI) NLCI Tamil fonts version 0.701
      - More positioning for vowel modifiers
      - One less language specific font
      19 Mar 2021 (Dev NLCI) NLCI Tamil fonts version 0.700
      - Improve generation of language specific fonts
      - Add vowel modifiers
      - Remove script prefix (TAML) from font names
      10 Jul 2019 (Dev NLCI) NLCI Tamil fonts version 0.500
      - Revise OpenType to match Graphite rendering
      - Enlarge single ring nukta by 21%
      - Position the pulli better on the ku ligature
      - Provide anusvara
      - Provide fewer language specific fonts
      (a specific font is only needed if the nukta is different).
      19 Jan 2019 (Dev NLCI) NLCI Tamil fonts version 0.401
      - Slightly expand and improve the character set
      - Move and adjust form of some of the nuktas
      - Provide language specific fonts
      04 Jan 2019 (Dev NLCI) NLCI Tamil fonts version 0.400
      - Keep the new nukta codepoint, but provide all nukta forms
      (including a new double ring) on the old codepoint as well.
      - Glyphs from the legacy font files are no longer scaled up
      - Glyphs from Latin fonts and Annapurna SIL are scaled 90%
      - Position marks better in Auvaiyar and Vaigai
      17 Aug 2018 (Dev NLCI) NLCI Tamil fonts version 0.303
      - Use two codepoints for nuktas, not just one
      18 May 2018 (Dev NLCI) NLCI Tamil fonts version 0.302
      - Changed default form of nukta
      - Kept the original units-per-em (UPM) from the legacy fonts
      - Increased default line spacing
      - Fixed Graphite rendering bug
      26 Mar 2018 (Dev NLCI) NLCI Tamil fonts version 0.301
      - Add many Latin and Devanagari characters
      - Latin glyphs in ThiruValluvar and Vaigai are from Gentium Book Basic (https://software.sil.org/gentium/)
      - Latin glyphs in Auvaiyar are from Charis SIL (https://software.sil.org/charis/)
      - Additional Latin glyphs are from Charis SIL (https://software.sil.org/charis/) and are removed in later versions
      - Indian Rupee Sign is from Annapurna SIL (https://software.sil.org/annapurna/)
      19 Mar 2018 (Dev NLCI) NLCI Tamil fonts version 0.300
      - Regenerate sources from original, hacked legacy fonts with an updated mapping
      14 Aug 2015 (Dev NLCI) NLCI Tamil fonts version 0.271
      - Latin glyphs are from Charis SIL (http://scripts.sil.org/CharisSILfont)
    </text>
  </description>
  <license url="http://scripts.sil.org/OFL" id="org.sil.ofl.1.1">
    <text lang="en">
      This Font Software is Copyright (c) 2009-2021, NLCI (http://www.nlci.in/fonts/)
      with Reserved Font Names "ThiruValluvar" and "Auvaiyar" and "Vaigai" and "NLCI".
      Latin glyphs in ThiruValluvar and Vaigai are Copyright (c) 2003-2019, SIL International (http://www.sil.org/)
      with Reserved Font Names "Gentium" and "SIL".
      Latin glyphs in Auvaiyar are Copyright (c) 1997-2019, SIL International (http://www.sil.org/)
      with Reserved Font Names "Charis" and "SIL".
      Indian Rupee Sign Copyright (c) 2007-2017, SIL International (http://www.sil.org/)
      with Reserved Font Names "Annapurna" and "SIL".
      Runic glyph Copyright (c) 2017 Google Inc. (http://www.google.com/get/noto/)
      
      This Font Software is licensed under the SIL Open Font License, Version 1.1.
      This license is copied below, and is also available with a FAQ at:
      http://scripts.sil.org/OFL
      
      
      -----------------------------------------------------------
      SIL OPEN FONT LICENSE Version 1.1 - 26 February 2007
      -----------------------------------------------------------
      
      PREAMBLE
      The goals of the Open Font License (OFL) are to stimulate worldwide
      development of collaborative font projects, to support the font creation
      efforts of academic and linguistic communities, and to provide a free and
      open framework in which fonts may be shared and improved in partnership
      with others.
      
      The OFL allows the licensed fonts to be used, studied, modified and
      redistributed freely as long as they are not sold by themselves. The
      fonts, including any derivative works, can be bundled, embedded,
      redistributed and/or sold with any software provided that any reserved
      names are not used by derivative works. The fonts and derivatives,
      however, cannot be released under any other type of license. The
      requirement for fonts to remain under this license does not apply
      to any document created using the fonts or their derivatives.
      
      DEFINITIONS
      "Font Software" refers to the set of files released by the Copyright
      Holder(s) under this license and clearly marked as such. This may
      include source files, build scripts and documentation.
      
      "Reserved Font Name" refers to any names specified as such after the
      copyright statement(s).
      
      "Original Version" refers to the collection of Font Software components as
      distributed by the Copyright Holder(s).
      
      "Modified Version" refers to any derivative made by adding to, deleting,
      or substituting -- in part or in whole -- any of the components of the
      Original Version, by changing formats or by porting the Font Software to a
      new environment.
      
      "Author" refers to any designer, engineer, programmer, technical
      writer or other person who contributed to the Font Software.
      
      PERMISSION &amp; CONDITIONS
      Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining
      a copy of the Font Software, to use, study, copy, merge, embed, modify,
      redistribute, and sell modified and unmodified copies of the Font
      Software, subject to the following conditions:
      
      1) Neither the Font Software nor any of its individual components,
      in Original or Modified Versions, may be sold by itself.
      
      2) Original or Modified Versions of the Font Software may be bundled,
      redistributed and/or sold with any software, provided that each copy
      contains the above copyright notice and this license. These can be
      included either as stand-alone text files, human-readable headers or
      in the appropriate machine-readable metadata fields within text or
      binary files as long as those fields can be easily viewed by the user.
      
      3) No Modified Version of the Font Software may use the Reserved Font
      Name(s) unless explicit written permission is granted by the corresponding
      Copyright Holder. This restriction only applies to the primary font name as
      presented to the users.
      
      4) The name(s) of the Copyright Holder(s) or the Author(s) of the Font
      Software shall not be used to promote, endorse or advertise any
      Modified Version, except to acknowledge the contribution(s) of the
      Copyright Holder(s) and the Author(s) or with their explicit written
      permission.
      
      5) The Font Software, modified or unmodified, in part or in whole,
      must be distributed entirely under this license, and must not be
      distributed under any other license. The requirement for fonts to
      remain under this license does not apply to any document created
      using the Font Software.
      
      TERMINATION
      This license becomes null and void if any of the above conditions are
      not met.
      
      DISCLAIMER
      THE FONT SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
      EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO ANY WARRANTIES OF
      MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT
      OF COPYRIGHT, PATENT, TRADEMARK, OR OTHER RIGHT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
      COPYRIGHT HOLDER BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY,
      INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL
      DAMAGES, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
      FROM, OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE FONT SOFTWARE OR FROM
      OTHER DEALINGS IN THE FONT SOFTWARE.
    </text>
  </license>
  <copyright>
    <text lang="en">
      This Font Software is Copyright (c) 2009-2021, NLCI (http://www.nlci.in/fonts/)
      with Reserved Font Names "ThiruValluvar" and "Auvaiyar" and "Vaigai" and "NLCI".
      Latin glyphs in ThiruValluvar and Vaigai are Copyright (c) 2003-2019, SIL International (http://www.sil.org/)
      with Reserved Font Names "Gentium" and "SIL".
      Latin glyphs in Auvaiyar are Copyright (c) 1997-2019, SIL International (http://www.sil.org/)
      with Reserved Font Names "Charis" and "SIL".
      Indian Rupee Sign Copyright (c) 2007-2017, SIL International (http://www.sil.org/)
      with Reserved Font Names "Annapurna" and "SIL".
      Runic glyph Copyright (c) 2017 Google Inc. (http://www.google.com/get/noto/)
    </text>
  </copyright>
</metadata>